no this is Marc Bennett Oh from the
circling night podcast and we have a
very special show for you today because
I have with me my friends and partners
Darryl do Wayne and David sweat walk so
you guys want to wave to the crowd it
denies Darryl playing hi I'm mrs. David
sweat lon okay okay guys so Darryl runs
an intentional community in Washington
DC called the Glo house at which I am
currently a very happy resident Darryl
was trained in Boulder integral t3
circling program and it would take your
attendance and was this one yeah in 83
okay got it
it would take me many minutes to listen
arrows various projects to interest all
just to name two of them he runs a very
large Burning Man community called camp
contact which includes both dance at KU
yoga and authentic relating components
and he's also creating community around
universal basic income on the blockchain
through a site of his called crypto ubi
dot org and David's when law as a
certified facilitator with Simone Europe
he's presented at the world future
Society South by Southwest Interactive
and the American creativity Association
David is committed to co-creating
effective practices of interdependent
human thriving I love that David so it's
a great pleasure to be with you both
today so here's what brings us together
so all three of us have been very
impacted by a recent podcast by Zachary
Stein who is writer and futurist on his
recent article which is called
love in a time between worlds on the
meta modern return to a metaphysics of
new Ross the full article was published
in the integral review and is also
available on Zach's website and next
time was recently interviewed by Michael
Garfield on the future fossils podcast
episode number 97 which is truly
wonderful podcast I actually became a
patreon supporter of Michael Garfield
after listening to this episode I was so
impressed and plus Michael needs money
as he is becoming a father soon so we do
want to support them do not oh
absolutely
okay good so I'm gonna start us off with
this 9 minute clip of Zach Stein on the
future fossils podcast which I'm sharing
with Michael's permission of course
now I was going to go today is I'm gonna
start with the audio clip and then
Darrell David and I are going to check
in and do what's called topical circling
which basically means we are going to
share ideas and impact and riff off each
other as it were and for those of you
unfamiliar with the idea of a topical
circle circle it is simply a circle in
which we allow more latitude for the
sharing of intellectual content and
ideas than we do in a regular or strict
relational meditation circle while still
holding connection intent as primary as
we do in regular circle meaning we're
sharing ideas but also you know impact
and hopefully valuing our connection
through this process so let me kick it
off with Zach Stein he's describing an
emergent philosophy called meta
modernism which is both a philosophy and
a movement which we believe has
significant implications on the practice
of circling and what we kind of do this
we live in a time between worlds and the
time in which the deepest questions
about what it means to be human
are kind of on the table again it's like
there are neurosciences seriously
suggesting we don't have free will and
arguing we can like change the legal
system which is predicated upon free
will by the way like we can change the
legal system we can change the legal
assistant to say that there is not free
well like serious suggestions and also
of course does God exists is there an
afterlife is there reincarnation
the nature of illness a nature healing
all of these things are scattered in
this kind of post truth cultural desert
where you're not sure which ones you
know if a thriving Oasis and which ones
uh you know basically a mirage and and
part of that student to the Internet and
I talked about the kind of structural
way that the post truth culture has been
generated by the very logic of
communication technology but it's also a
moment properly speaking in the
evolution of culture which is to say
it's a rightful overcoming
the singular logic and logo centrism and
mono centrosome of modernity and so the
postmodern proliferation of perspectives
and the and they can comment and
confusion is is par for the course but
it's of course a dangerous critical
global path now through the confusion
back to reality and so I talked about a
return to eros and a return to a
metaphysics in which not just physical
things are real but also the things that
populate the human interiors and
especially the constellation of emotions
around love that these things are as
real as any of the physical properties
and so this gets to again the nature of
reality and the need to have it more
nuance to metaphysics that doesn't just
materiality and meaningless matter in
motion and Darwinian dynamics that
includes meaning value the interior T's
consciousness
etc right totally so yeah absolutely I
mean the framing of the papers in terms
of the cultural epic or kind of
historical period designation right
versus saying slice history and and you
know the history is a very complicated
stream you can slice it into periods or
a box and so there's a group that is you
know mostly in kind of Europe and there
are there's some American
representatives who have kind of dubbed
the emerging period of history that we
are entering as meta modern and I think
it's an important conversation because I
was convinced long ago by Habermas and
others that what we call post-modernism
is actually most of the traits of
modernity just with the volume turned
really way up like his subjects you know
subjectivity increases you know
contextualization and increases instead
of one perspective you get many
perspectives not the pre perspective on
pre-modern where the individual in the
group refused but this hyper
individualism flourishes more under
Smothers so this idea that there must be
an a cultural turning in which we can
critique both the postmodern and the
modern and we can value both the
postmodern and the modern
which is to say there's something that's
distinctly non modern or meta modern
which will get a name later we're not
sure what it will be that's the way I
hold it then an integral theory which I
discovered a very young like in my
twenties like I was twenty literally
when I read in sex culture spirituality
um you know this was I see this now is a
species of meta modern philosophy and
there were many varieties of meta modern
philosophy not all of them are integrals
here intro theory is one that I started
with and like a lot but there are other
candidates meta modern you know meta
modern world views and so we know one of
the things that makes a cultural period
a period is that there's some coherence
to the structure of it and so this list
you talk about in the beginning of my
paper it's it's a list of the things
that kind of characterized the meta
modern historical periods view of
reality in science and it's distinctly
different from the postmodern in the
modern right so the the modern view of
science is that science is truth period
like in the periods very definite the
postmodern view of science is like
science is one view dot dot dot right
like there's actually many and Sciences
one the meta monter view essentially
tries to say that both of those are true
and as you were saying within specific
context science works it actually
discovers things the problem is that
it's overstepped its context and so it
takes for example of an experiment that
was done in a very closed condition in a
laboratory and pretends that what's
discovered there applies to radically
open systems outside the laboratory
right you get pharmaceuticals in the
drinking water because we're acai Slee
push this thing through
no that's and that's perfect example you
know and that's exactly the danger of
the modern view which is correct in the
laboratory guys like don't take em this
other postmodern seize that moment of
error in the modern and then once the
thorough science
the window completely the meta modernist
says hold on something happened in the
laboratory like we we have to actually
pay attention to the moment of truth in
the modern and then you know
contextualize it with the postmodern you
know alternative which says well let's
do a bunch of other experiments let's do
things that don't even look like
experiments right and let's look at
methodologies that are non quantitative
and methodologies that are
phenomenological and purely subjective
which a modernist would never even touch
so you get this proliferation of methods
proliferation of perspectives all good
but now how a total fragmentation and
like out of the Academy comes totally
confusing gobbledygook about what is the
nature of the human well you know I
think it was internet recording at least
a half a dozen time and every time it
kind of moves me and excites me there's
nothing where it's very powerful yeah so
so David want you I kick us off with
your impact on that and if anything else
it's up for you by the way we're not
limiting this conversation in any way
yeah thank you
you know I first just want to say you
know thank you guys I've been listening
to Michael Garfield for a while but this
this conversation I'm excited that it's
that it stirred up more people as well
and it really does it there's a vibrancy
that zach Stein brings to the
conversation
that I think has been missing up till
now you know I like both of you I've
been studying will prefer a while and
actually participated in some of his
courses back in 2005 and I've had this
sense that I that there is some way to
bring all of this to a more ideal way
that we can relate to each other I mean
my whole my whole thing of wanting to
have a well I'll say I was impacted as
well by Buckminster Fuller and the whole
sense that we want to we want a world
that works for everyone
and there's a way that that has always
felt a little bit theoretical and too
far off and there's a frustration around
that and and even with participating
with Wilbur and everything else there's
just this way in which it feels like
it's we can't seem to get the
grounded route of how do we get started
on that listen as it heads on sticks yes
yes yes yes and so my experience was
circling was a way for me my
introduction to it came at an intuition
of saying I think there's something my
body has to contribute to the
conversation that I don't know how to
hear and actually slowing down enough to
listen to myself while I was relating to
others profoundly shifted the way that I
listen and it's in after three years of
practice I find that I'm continuing to
deepen in that and so it's really this
powerful way that I can see connecting
to others really acquires a deep
connecting to myself first what was
powerful in listening to Zack Stein's
interview with with Michael Garfield was
the recognition that we're doing that
now that we feel like suddenly we have a
collective way of doing that like the
need to get to a point of being able to
hear what it is that we as a collective
what we as a species want is a deep way
of its it's like in this moment I mean
it makes so much sense that we're in a
post truth era and I'm from where we
have been so far it's like if we could
just establish the ground rules for how
to interact with one another then we get
going and it's like we're finally at the
point I feel like we're finally at the
point where that's no longer that's no
longer the the goal we're giving up on
the notion of what are the essential
ground rules to get started all we need
to do is start with where we're at all
we need to do is start with right here
and so that's where I'm super excited to
see what arises when we actually just
meet each other meet myself look in the
mirror very clearly and say here's
here's where we're at
thank you David that's beautiful what
I'm what I'm resonating with is slow
down long enough to notice what's going
on within you and that's all we need to
do so let's just let's just put that
into the space and let it simmer for a
bit okay thank you yes cool what are
your thoughts now yeah so great great
stuff there David particularly the
embodiment part in listening to our
bodies and not knowing how to interpret
what our bodies are saying I recently
you have have ongoing also had a
frustration with language and there's
this idea that language has so much
power but I think a lot of people give
it too much credence and then some other
people too encoded enough credence and I
was very interested to hear about this
book you mentioned something about the
alphabet and and the body David yeah the
alphabet versus the goddess bye laughs
great def a my reading list now and and
I want to contrast the intellectual
aspects of Bucky and and Wilbur with
with also wanting to get embodied what
is the embodied mr. filler look like for
us how can can we'll bring it more
embodied and maybe that's what Zack is
kind of able to reach here in this
that's certainly what I'm wanting no
matter what we do but I think there's a
lot to be said for kind of thinking
about haha like that just that question
how does anybody in a given interaction
get what they want and how are we
creating more than win-win-win for you
one for me and one for the rest of the
world in nature interactions and yeah
but that's really complex and we're
enable we're gonna do a place where
we're able to have technology and spirit
and human connection and awareness of
our bodies enough that it's possible and
this is maybe what zach is saying when
he's talking about kind of this new new
return to metaphysics there's some some
new like I get deeper in his podcast if
he says something about or we mentioned
this that there's this in post-modernism
everything's okay or everything is what
it is people are just who they are and
they are and we still have that yet
there is some unifying sense of the
human or of Venus and while ago I was
wondering you know what would the human
mission statement be or what would the
Earth's mission Satan beginning to like
a Gaia hypothesis sort of thinking and
what if everybody knew what that was or
was able to interact with it at some
level in each of the decisions that we
make day to day to to co-create
consciousness if you dare though that
was very inspiring for me as well as
sort of this idea of a triple win me me
you in the world I don't that so so
here's what I want to say so
listening to Zach Stein me me feel less
alone in that I can see now that I'm
part of this movement which he calls
meta modernism and which I liken
essentially to the planetary merchants
of integral to your consciousness as an
integral theory including transcend of
left and right politics right and this
is a worldview that I feel has quite
profound implications to the theory and
practice of circling so this is what
we're gonna talk about this is a
circling podcast so I'm developing two
platforms just very briefly one is a
circling guide in which I'm basically
trying to educate and inspire people to
learn about and practice circling and
not just in formal circles but also with
their loved ones and business partner is
a practice that I have called in my book
guerrilla circling as in guerrilla
warfare of the underground
the Louisville Revolutionary Army haha
and I was giving the thumbs up here and
my other platform is the man-woman
education platform and I could say a lot
more about history was circling in my
ongoing love affair with the practice of
circling and with a circling community
but let's um let's get back to Metta
modernist philosophy here and its
implications so from my perspective it
and in that time really helped me to see
this is circling to me is a very precise
and very powerful application only the
instantiation of this meta modern
philosophy into the field of human
loving of the fundamental challenge of
learning how to love and be loved
including all the obstacles that are put
in our way which of course include
developmental trauma and/or social
conditioning and what I am really trying
to do in my life is to bring this
question of love back into the public
conversation but in a practical way
which i think zach is doing and this is
really what has me so excited I mean
it's very intellectual but it's also it
really resonates with me in a lot of
fundamental ways um and this is this is
what I'm so excited about circly because
I believe that certainly is perhaps the
fastest and most direct way of becoming
a more loving person or learning those
skills and becoming a more whole and
more complex and more generous more
injury-related and happier person and I
think you guys thanks Darrell and I
think you guys know I'm a circle
chuckling groupie and you guys are not
very far behind particularly David yes
so I'll just give one frame here and
then all I'll just I'll move to the
topic of circle the frame which is
meaningful to me in which illustrates
the nature of circling as a integral or
meta modern practice and so I will mean
one of the core principles of circling
which is welcome everything
welcome everything right um but for me
for this to work it needs to be a very
active woken up welcomed everything so
it needs to be done within a relational
container in which we truly attempt to
understand in connects and connect with
what the other is bringing so this would
be in contrast for instance to a
postmodern approach such as Fritz Perls
famous quote you do your thing and I do
mine and if we meet it's
beautiful and if we don't do bad right
so it sounds good but somehow to me that
doesn't satisfy because it doesn't
actually speak our demon need to connect
and to relate to each other through our
differences and to find common ground in
our shared humanity which is really what
it uses which is really where the joy is
so I think let me just put that into the
space and see what we want to go from
here I know you David you were relating
a very powerful experience you had
earlier it was some project with the
hazel grace in Austin I don't know if
you want to say more about that yeah
actually I would love to because I think
it speaks really powerfully to what what
we're talking about here and it's really
starting to see how this authentic
relating movement is starting to bring
to the fore practices that that dude
touched deeply into that eras
the thing that I would say you know just
introducing that and hearing you Marcos
the thing that really stands out to me
is this conversation is like I feel like
we're ready to really get started having
this conversation because I'm finally
able to listen to myself it's like I'm
no longer requiring that you be some
certain way before I engage in the
conversation I actually can be in a
relation with myself in a way that
brings me forward and now I'm actually
available to have the conversation that
said the the the prod the the course
that I took with hazel Crazy Eights is
is called healing the divide it was it's
born out of I'll go and say the
project and the project put
together its men and women actually
healing the shame around sexuality and
while I am aware of my own sense of
shame around sexuality I had no idea how
central that was to the difficulty I
find it connecting to other people and
as I the the day is a the course is
really a day of men first speaking in
women witnessing women then speaking in
men with
missing with specific questions and the
specific questions you know and guide me
to a deeper experience of what what is
my actual authentic experience of myself
as I have grown up through this way in
which I orient to my sexuality the thing
that moved me the most about it was
opening myself up giving having been
given the opportunity to speak first had
to be to really delve into my experience
of my sexuality with other men opened me
up in some profound ways my heart space
just expanded and from that place
actually moving into witnessing the
women I just noticed how powerful and
distinct the experiences or that
listening and I was able to hear myself
the here new subtle nuances of ways in
which I wanted to listen to myself in it
it's a thing that's really powerful is
just how much that I crave that I mean
it's satisfied some deep yearning inside
of me that'll let that just brought
tears to my eyes it just allowed me to
actually hear what it was that I wanted
from connection and then it's it brought
tears to my when you to my eyes even
when you first spoke about this and what
I'm hearing is some the women speaking
you know it's coming to me now actually
the grief is that the women speaking
reflected something inside you then you
found a listening form yes
yeah absolutely yeah yeah that's
beautiful yeah it's the I don't know if
it captures it but the sense is if if
you if you will but listen to me we can
really dance right which is what they
want right right that that's a sense
right yes yeah
and the challenge there is us opening to
that request and then making the request
and then making the request and wait
it's actually enrolling right right and
they're my own personal practice has
been I'm actually hearing parts of
myself make the same request
you know I am I'm aware that I've been
attempting to solve this problem from an
intellectual space it's circling has
given me an a capacity for listening
deeper than that and now that you know
what I would I the way that I frame it
is I am actually looking for authentic
partnership between my heart and my
brain yeah yeah yeah do you have any
thoughts on that Darryl or any impact at
the moment I think a lot most of our
life's mission humans is to integrate
the connections between each of our
chakras pretty nebulous easy wasters I
know I get it but where do we where is
the next step in that or how are we able
to better know I have this fantasy of
little chakra watch that tells us how
we're doing nice glowing stuff maybe
someday we have better awarenesses of
that that can be measured and shown and
coached as we until we do we have
circling as the tool to get real and
let those with holes become not
withholding that's that really is
beautiful it it reminds me you know just
in saying that while the the practice
has been how can I have authentic
partnership between my heart and my in
my mind you know some since my third eye
in my heart okay okay there's another
part that the workshop with hazel Crazy
Eights did with me yesterday which is
including the second chakra noticing the
way in which that makes it challenging
and really what what you're saying it
one that really excites me from the
perspective noticing the interplay of
all of the all of the chakras as I'm
going and in some way the I'm curious if
there's some way to do a topical sock
circling yeah of the different chakras
there's really a way of including that
that I think is a powerful way of
opening myself up to myself into into
into the world yeah so yeah so I mean we
we sort of start with that sign in and
this is X line and then we we seem to be
you know moving to the topic of the
masculine feminine split you know
hearten head and if you allow me I would
introduce another frame here
there's always spoken to me quite
powerfully this is from the Course in
Miracles nobody's field alone nobody
field alone right I think why this fits
to me so powerfully is it's just the
recognition that we do not exist in a
vacuum
that were deeply impacted by the social
conditioning and the moons and emotional
conditions of the people in an
environment right and so contrast this
to a postmodern idea that we all create
our own reality for example you know
subtext you and you alone are
responsible for your healing and
transformation that's the subsets of you
create your own reality which of course
is true you know we obviously we do
agreed on reality we have a choice now
we respond to the people in events and
so forth and
and we're also you know we also have to
respond creatively to the challenges
arising out of our you know character
ology and traumas and so forth however
the idea that we create our own reality
is a vast oversimplification of the
truth about humanity and it and that
could actually be damaging you can be
damaging because we can take this idea
that we create on reality first of all
and you sitting guilt and shame
ourselves right when we're seemingly
failing to create our reality that we
like right um and it can also lead to a
kind of hyper individualism in which we
can imagine we can solve our problems by
ourselves by some you know new and
improved structure of thought form right
which in most cases is false that's not
gonna happen
you know in most cases the most direct
way to solve our problems is to start
showing up to ourselves and other people
with more honesty and vulnerability okay
I call this you know I call this
communicating truth with care and care
with truth and you know David when you
talk about slowing down to listen to
yourself that that reminds me of this
thank you yeah that's really powerful I
love I love that that observation that
just from the postmodern perspective we
create our own reality is is a way in
which disconnecting from it's a way that
could be used to disconnect from myself
and it can be a victim blaming and I'm
independent I don't need you and all you
know since you're creating your own the
rally to stop it up and then
let's get let's actually just connect
right so both of those have a way of
doing thing is this this actually speaks
Marco you know and I yep you know I've
talked about that idea this concept that
I that I have the opposable self yes yes
talk about that in smooth way so that
that sense of the opposable self like an
opposable thumb are distinct
perspectives that come together and if
I'm not aware of the connection it comes
across as opposition allottee of
either-or thinking in which there's a
there's a sense of head-butting and
fighting over the tree
and from the point of contact where the
you know if I imagine where my fingers
and thumb touch that from Metta
opposition ality if there's a fight I
actually can't get the sense of your
perspective because I'm asserting my
perspective so much but the real sense
of it is the dance happens whenever I
find our commonality I really the Union
at the other end which is really deep
within myself so the deep sense of where
I'm actually connected to myself is
specifically the point that feels most
challenged in that oppositional
perspective and when I can be with
myself there suddenly something opens up
in something shifts and I can hear
myself and hear you newly and the dance
really becomes possible right right so
back to you know just to reiterate the
idea of the emotional possible brain our
brains are designed to be opposable so
that the two parts can get into
connection and reach a higher
integration yes right right and and when
they're just off there's a sense of
dissonance and actually it's the
dissonance if I'm listening closely to
the dissonance and how the in dissonance
impacts me rather than trying to fix the
dissonance I actually can become in
harmony just from noticing the point of
impact sweet yeah listen it doe
alright the subject comes up yeah I
talked about that a lot as well there's
another there's another aspect of this
which there's a there's a way in which
what you were saying before that freedom
of choice that exact science speaks to
this as well right there's a we're
starting to get to a point where
freewill is actually brought into
question yeah I love that that the idea
that the legal system is toy based on
existence of free will yet there's now
this idea and I want to
learn more about it that that maybe we
can't count on free will and holding
people accountable right well in that so
and I've wrestled with this myself so
many times what I notice here that's
interesting is as I look at it it looks
like where I have freedom is in choosing
the context with which I'm interpreting
the frame you know what this
conversation is about
so the impact the impact I actually can
shift right what happened happened
what's in the room is in the room but I
can actually listen from different
perspectives and settled into myself so
the point of opposed ability in a way
can shift in a way that opens up the
conversation and it's specifically for
me being attached to one specific
perspective that makes that hard to do
but when I notice I can relax the
attachment to one perspective I then can
allow other perspectives to arise and
bring myself from that from that frame
for me real truth is paradox
I don't believe something until I find
some contradiction to it or some anti
truth to it I don't think real truth is
just simple statements of the sky is
blue right when they think that's
exactly what exacts then guys next time
is saying you know real truth is uh
extraordinaire in the complex in both
modernism and post-modernism you know or
maybe you know make a farce of the job
of actually finding real truths right so
you know I think my thought on this
guy's is I actually pretty firmly
believe that we have much less free will
and then we imagine because we're just
basically you know controlled by both
social conditioning and by what's a
culture you know physio physiological
patterns you know obsessive brain loops
physiologic loops etc addictions
third the third new thing is is our gut
enzyme our gut yes yes well what's it
called the brain stomach link that
there's a lot of research and discovery
being made about that like we almost
have a second plane it we almost have a
second brain in a digestive system it's
exact it's not a brain it's a collection
of microorganisms that are not right
exactly
yes so anyway but this mover it's back
to what what you were saying David is
that you know even even if it's only
true that we have 10% of the free well
we want by gaining awareness of those
areas where that may be true
paradoxically it gives us more free well
absolutely right and I mean it'll
certainly give us more peace and
happiness in relaxation because because
not hitting ourselves for being the way
we are right right right you know you
know I've been you know I've been trying
for thirty years to do an hour of yoga
upon awakening and I haven't succeeded
yet but I still hope to reach that state
one day in fact like start tomorrow who
knows why not yeah it's so absolutely
that's that's exactly right that sense
that by actually naming that point it
feels like I mean the thing that's
amazing is it's I almost want to fight
against the idea that I don't have free
will I want to I want to you know it
reminds me of in the in the matrix maybe
when Morpheus asks neo do you want to be
in control of your life and I do you you
know you want they sent there's a sense
that yes I know what you mean and that
feeling that you're out of control
is almost untenable that you don't have
some say in in your experience and if if
I'm not actually willing to look there
then I'm then I am at the effect of my
circumstance a cliff you're not even
willing to contemplate the question
you're automatically a victim of that
question right thank it's beautiful
actually what's that movie again
actually it's powerful it really is no
it's not it's really
movie really it's a psychologically very
very brilliant movie there's I want to
bring it back Marco - we had an earlier
conversation about this idea of the cult
I wanna I wanna yes yes let's let's
let's wrap it up with that if we could
because I don't got we got some good
content here so so part of where this
comes to mind I mean it's in in my mind
all the time when I think about
intentional community and utopian
visions I'm aware that there's something
that's that's unaddressed in that
there's something that seems to go
sideways almost every time and and
particularly just recently I've been
watching the mini series on Netflix for
wild walled country where Osho or Shree
Rajneesh has been you know it's such it
with so sideways yeah and yeah I watched
that I watched that for six hours
straight by the way David I think four
am wow that's pretty it's a it's deeply
powerful and impacting just to watch
from both sides right the thing that's
so amazing is watching the way in which
both the rajneeshees and the Oregonians
were willing to fort their values in
order to get to some perceived some
perceived need met and completely
obliterating both of their truths the
state of driz in order to get to that
and and and so the question for me is
how do we be aware of that so that that
doesn't sneak up and I mean it's so it
was so interesting you it's clearly a
point where they're not acting from free
will okay and so the question for me is
how do we start this conversation in a
way that doesn't lead to that same kind
of self delusional chasing myself down
that rabbit hole and losing the the
essence of what it is that I'm really
after
yeah and that's sort of the topic of
really what we're trying we're trying to
achieve here the accessible brain I'm
holding the two perspective
simultaneously and well so the shift
we've made in the conversation here is
about taking that freewill part to the
community and what point does the
community take away free will from its
members through cultish or influence or
culture of that community and at what
forty Turk are people yeah wait and I'm
extremely happy that you named that
Darryl as you are you know the official
leader of the camp contacts cult yeah
sure sure sure as as it were I don't and
and I worked very hard and asked myself
constantly how does this community of
dancers and and people going to Burning
Man festivals exercise its free will and
we're not a democratic we don't use a
democratic model we don't use consensus
per se and and you know the other part
of that question is how can we make it
most efficient to people do that so
there's things like to AH Krissy and how
does just tributed leadership happen or
collaborative leadership happen and the
things like holacracy and Scioscia cracy
come to mind but I'm not sure those are
are suitable for that either
all the way but there might be some
parts of it that can come and and then
how does this expand out and to the rest
of society which leads me back to that
that question what is the the biological
based mission statement what what is
what are all of our organisms trying to
do day in day out and how can we make it
more efficient or more practical and not
waste people's energies or have people
going off in different directions that
that don't serve that that greater
mission
and you know what they're like I gotta
give you a big shout out a big
appreciation for you know for the work
you do I can contact no one is getting
paid here not even you in fact you're
losing money at this contribute right
lots of ways
yeah and you know basically bringing you
know bringing together you know quite
large group of people in in a
collaborative venture that includes you
know all the logistical support and
programming for you know braiding
mannequin contacts and all the different
regional burns that that you do that we
do and really trying to optimize the
transformational value and yeah you know
that's a very very complex problem how
do we keep this thing going with you
know some kind of reasonable level of
chaos doesn't overwhelm and and operates
at least as efficiently as we can
well at the same time maximizing you
know people's contributions right and
this is and this is a problem that I
know you think about every day and maybe
every minute of the day alright sure and
sometimes you screw up and I've seen you
suffer when you screw up I'd like to say
is well you know there's a this year at
Burning Man was the first my first
interaction with camp contact and there
are two things that come to mind really
one of them is it truly is the art of
emergent relational thriving right just
this beautiful way in which third the
hole comes together and it in your
presence is so subtle from the from the
from a governance perspective right
you're almost invisible from a
governance perspective but as I watch
what you're doing so beautifully weaving
the pieces together and kind of
listening for that conversation that
allows people to step forward
continually and each person kind of
recognizes in a way what do I feel is
missing that I want to contribute to the
space and that
contributes to the whole it's just
beautiful so yeah I'm mirror mark oh
really what technology from thank you
powerful really sweet words and yeah
I'll take them in a little bit and I
also want to push him right back at you
okay guys so you saw something that you
liked what are you guys doing to do the
same thing someplace else
mmm thank you perfect accepted okay no
okay guys you know I'm feeling fall I'm
feeling happy I'm you know I'm ready to
to to stop there if there's any kind of
burning things you guys want to do and
then we'll move to debrief I'm gonna
record the the debrief but then we'll
publish it depending on depending okay
yeah thank you Mark
thank you David I think we're onto
something powerful here and I look
forward to future versions of this
another top thank you yeah same here
thanks same here extremely thrilled yes
okay Margo
maybe I've already checked out just the
same happy in fault and you guys have
anything anything more I'll say I feel
like in a real way this is just barely
scratching the surface and yet it feels
like a significant scratch it feels like
a toehold into something very powerful
to continue the conversation so I'm
excited I'm excited about this moment of
time and where we're at and and kind of
a set in the context for continuing
beyond now I think we're I mean I think
we're sort of in significant alignment
about what we want to create and now
we're gonna do it yeah which is pretty
pretty pretty significant